[Music]
Hello friends, Namaskar Menraj Patel, welcome to
your own channel Shreeji
Assure. So, suppose you have purchased a health
insurance policy, but for some
reason, you want to cancel it.
But you are wondering whether it is
possible to cancel the health insurance policy.
If yes, will you
get a refund for the premium paid? The answers to all your
questions are in this video. In this
video, we will explain
when and how the purchased health insurance policy can be cancelled and
how much refund you will get.
Your first question is
whether you can cancel your health insurance policy. The
answer is, you
can absolutely do so. Insurance companies provide their customers the
flexibility to cancel almost all their plans even after purchasing them. If
you want to cancel your health insurance policy,
your policy will be
cancelled. There is no hassle in this.
But the question is, if you cancel the policy
some time after purchasing the policy or in the middle of it, will
you get a
refund? Look, it is obvious that you have earned the benefit of your hard work.  If you
can't sacrifice your earnings, you'll
definitely be worried about a refund.
You'll receive a refund upon canceling your policy. However, the amount of
refund will depend on the
time of policy term. You
can cancel your health insurance policy at any time during the policy term, but you can only receive a refund if
you have
n't filed a clean chit during the policy term. Now, let's move on to the process of
canceling a health insurance policy. There are
two processes for canceling a policy: one is to
cancel the policy before the free look period and the
other is to cancel it after the free look period. The
free look period lasts from
15 to 30 days from the date of purchase.
During this period, if you are not satisfied with the
terms and conditions of your health insurance policy
or anything else,
you can request your insurance company to
cancel your policy. You'll receive the
amount you paid for free.
You may not receive the full amount. The
company may also charge stamp duty, initial medical expenses, and other fees.  There will be
some deduction for checkup and insurance risk charge.
Secondly, after the free look period is
over, if you
want to cancel the policy, then
you will
get a parcel i.e. some percentage refund based on the number of days you have canceled. Let me tell you here
that every insurance company can have
different percentage for the particular period of coverage.
So you saw
how easy it is to cancel a health insurance policy and you also get a refund. So
friends, if you liked the video, then
like the video
and share it with all your friends and family members.
If you have any suggestion or question, then
let's talk in the comment section. Also, please
subscribe to our channel Shriji and
I will meet you again
with some interesting video. Till then,
thank you so much.